A Guide to the Papers of Sir Fitzroy Maclean 1827-1966
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- Career & Personal Papers
  - British Military Mission to Yugoslavia
    - Top Secret File--Miscellaneous Reports and Minutes of Meeting between Field Marshal Alexander and Tito 1944-1945 (Box 2)
    - Top Secret File--Supplies to JANL 1945 (Box 2)
    - Top Secret File--Miscellaneous Telegrams 1944-1945 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence with Evelyn Waugh 1944-1945, 1948 (Box 2)
    - News clippings ca. 1944-1945 (Box 2)
  - Special Refugee Commission
    - Correspondence 1947 Jan-Feb (Box 2)
      re Appointments and Impact on Service to Constituency
    - File on Individual Cases and Other Correspondence 1947 Feb-Nov (Box 2)
    - Outgoing Telegrams to the Foreign Office 1947 Oct-Dec (Box 2)
    - Incoming Telegrams from the Foreign Office 1947 Oct-1948 Jan (Box 2)
    - Personal and Confidential File 1947 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, Reports, and Articles 1947 Jan-1948, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Report to Foreign Secretary Ernest Bevin 1948 Feb 11 (Box 3)
    - Draft of a Speech to a Parliamentary Committee on the Refugee Problem 1947 Dec-1948 Jan (Box 3)
  - Political Correspondence
    - Correspondence: Lancaster By-Election 1941 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence and Speeches: General Election of 1945 1942-1946 (Box 3)
    - Article "Left Hand-Right Hand" [1947] (Box 3)
      re the Threat of Soviet Expansion in Asia
    - Drafts of a Speech on the Berlin Crisis and Soviet Threat 1948 (Box 3)
    - Articles and Correspondence 1950-1954 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence: Winston Churchill to Fitzroy Maclean and a copy of his response 1951 Nov (Box 3)
    - Memo 1952 (Box 3)
      re Irregular Warfare and Correspondence with Field Marshall Earl Alexander of Tunis and Others
    - Speech on Irregular Warfare [1952] (Box 3)
    - Correspondence 1952-1958 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence: Letter of Congratulations from Fitzroy Maclean to Winston Churchill & Telegram from Winston Churchill to F.M. 1953 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence: Letter of Jack Coville, Secretary to Winston Churchill, announcing Churchill's Resignation 1955 Apr 5 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence: the Lovat Scouts (Scottish S.A.S. Regiment) 1955-1956 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence 1959-1995 (Box 3)
    - Article on Conscription 1961 Mar 9 (Box 3)
    - Transcript of "The Week in Westminster" 1962 Feb 24 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence: L.L. Lemnitzer, Chairman of U.S. Joint Chiefs of Staff 1962 Mar 17 (Box 3)
      re Vietnam War
    - Correspondence: Robert Kennedy and Edward Kennedy 1963, 1971 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence: John V. Lindsay, Henry Jackson, Averell Harriman and a U.S. Senator 1965-1978 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence: Kosygin's Visit to Scotland 1967 Feb (Box 3)
    - Speech in the House of Commons 1968 Aug 26 (Box 3)
      re the Soviet Invasion of Czechoslovakia
    - Correspondence with Anthony Head 1970-1971 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence with Archbishop Lord Fisher of Lambeth 1971 Jul (Box 3)
    - Notebook: Draft of Memos 1973 (Box 3)
      re Interview with Vice-President Bodnaras of Romania; Meeting with Tito; and Draft Article on Sino-Soviet Border
    - Correspondence and Report 1973 Nov-Dec (Box 3)
      Parlimentary Delegation to Romania
    - Correspondence: Harold Wilson 1975-1983 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence: Margaret Thatcher 1975-1990 (Box 3)
    - News clippings 1991, 1995 (Box 3)
      re Winston Churchill
    - Correspondence: John Major 1993 Apr-Jun (Box 3)
      re E.C. Grants for Argyll and Bute
    - Correspondence: Andreas Simou (Doctoral Student) 1996 (Box 3)
      re Consideration of Fitzroy Maclean as Governor of Cyprus
    - Letter n.d. (Box 3)
      re a Resignation to Veronica Maclean
  - VIP Material
    - Princess Margaret to Veronica Maclean and Memorabilia of Funeral Services for King George VI 1952 Feb (Box 3)
    - Program for a Dinner with Queen Elizabeth II 1956 Nov 27 (Box 3)
    - Princess Margaret to Fitzroy and Veronica Maclean 1959-1960 (Box 3)
    - Christmas Cards (all with photographs) from Elizabeth, the Queen Mother to Fitzroy and Veronica Maclean 1980-1994 (Box 3)
    - Princess Margaret to Fitzroy and Veronica Maclean and Program for the Visit of Princess Margaret to Argyll and Bute in August 1984 1984-1985 (Box 4)
    - Elizabeth the Queen Mother to Fitzroy and Veronica Maclean, including letters about rhododendron gifts 1977-1995 (Box 4)
    - Prince Charles to Fitzroy and Veronica Maclean 1978-1981, 1995 (Box 4)
    - Prince Charles--Thank you note and Memorabilia from the wedding of Charles and Diana 1981 Jul 29 (Box 4)
    - Clementine Churchill to Fitzroy and Veronica Maclean 1953-1963, n.d. (Box 4)
    - Mary Churchill Soames to Fitzroy Maclean [1950s] (Box 4)
      re his serving as godfather to her daughter, Charlotte
    - Mary Churchill Soames to Fitzroy and Veronica Maclean 1978 (Box 4)
    - Mary Churchill Soames to Fitzroy and Veronica Maclean, with Program for Winston Churchill's funeral and other Memorabilia 1965 Jan-Feb (Box 4)
    - Program from "The Other Club's" Dinner to Mark the 50th Anniversary of Winston Churchill's Appointment as Prime Minister 1990 May 10 (Box 4)
    - Memorabilia of Mikhail Gorbachev's Visits to London and Edinburgh; Speech welcoming Gorbachev to Aberdeen 1983-1993 (Box 4)
    - Memorabilia of Ceremonial to Commemorate the Fiftieth Anniversary of the End of World War II 1995 May 5 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence of Ardeshir Zahedi 1963, n.d. (Box 4)
    - New Year's card with photograph from the King and Queen of Nepal to Fitzroy and Veronica Maclean n.d. (Box 4)
    - Lauren Bacall autograph note to Fitzroy Maclean n.d. (Box 4)
    - Autograph of Yuri Gagarin n.d. (Box 4)
  - Yugoslavia & Tito Related Material
    - Correspondence and Report on Charges Against Consul General Robert Kronholz 1946 (Box 4)
    - Fitzroy Maclean to Ralph Deakin of The Times1947 (Box 4)
      re British Press Coverage of Yugoslavia
    - Correspondence with Major-General C.D. Packard 1948 (Box 4)
      re Simic Cureija
    - Top Secret Memo of a Meeting with Tito 1949 May (Box 4)
    - Memo of Meetings with Tito and Mates 1950 Sep (Box 4)
    - Transcripts and Memo 1953 Oct-Nov (Box 4)
      re Visit with Tito, with note from Jack Coville, Secretary to Winston Churchill
    - Correspondence of Alexander Rankovic and Fitzroy Maclean, with a New Year's card 1960-1963 (Box 4)
    - Jovanka Broz (wife of Tito) to Veronica Maclean 1961 Jan 24 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, including Edward Vasey of the Foreign Office and Michael Cresswell (British Ambassador) 1962-1963 (Box 4)
    - Field Marshall Montgomery 1964 Aug 8 (Box 4)
      re Tito
    - Correspondence and Research Material 1967-1971 (Box 4)
      re Korcula
    - Memo of Interview with Tito 1968 Sep 20 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence r 1968 Oct-Dec (Box 4)
      re Visit to Yugoslavia for 25th Anniversary of National Liberation, includes photographs of Maclean and Willian Deakin
    - Correspondence 1970 (Box 4)
      Decoration Awarded to Fitzroy Maclean
    - Correspondence 1970, 1972 (Box 4)
      Proposed British Decorations of Yugoslavs
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1970-1971 (Box 4)
      re Yugoslav Students in Britain
    - Correspondence and Accounts by Fitzroy Maclean and Others 1970-1971, 2 folders (Box 4)
      re Allied Mission to Yugoslavia in World War II for Muzej AVNOJ
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, including Phyllis Auty, William Deakin and Vladko Velebit 1970-1973 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence 1971-1988, 2 folders (Box 5)
      re Korcula, Yugoslavia, Town Twinning with Argyll and Bute, Scotland
    - Draft Proposals in Support of Tito for Nobel Peace Prize by D. Vidic, Yugoslav Ambassador [1972] (Box 5)
    - Correspondence 1973 (Box 5)
      re Maclean's Efforts in Support of Tito for the Nobel Peace Prize
    - Correspondence re Conference 1972-1973 (Box 5)
      re British Policy towards the Balkan Resistance Movements
    - Fitzroy Maclean's Paper for the Conference re British Policy towards the Balkan Resistance Movement 1973 Jul (Box 5)
    - Papers by Participants for the Conference re British Policy towards the Balkan Resistance Movement 1973 Jul, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Confidential Memo 1973 Dec 12 (Box 5)
      re Meeting with Tito
    - Correspondence 1973 (Box 5)
      re Research and Annual Summaries (Copies) of Events in Yugoslavia, 1957-1972
    - Interview with Nada Radosevich in Serbo-Croation 1976 (Box 5)
    - Zivan Berisavljevic, Yugoslav Ambassador, to Fitzroy Maclean on behalf of Tito 1977 Sep 12 (Box 5)
    - Newspaper Articles on Political and Economic Issues Prior to Margaret Thatcher's Trip 1977 Jul-Dec (Box 5)
    - Briefing Papers for Margaret Thatcher's Trip 1977 Nov (Box 5)
    - Correspondence and Memorabilia 1977 Nov-Dec (Box 5)
      re Margaret Thatcher's Trip, with Official Program
    - Speech of Margaret Thatcher at Dinner in Belgrade 1977 Dec (Box 5)
    - Correspondence 1978 Sep (Box 6)
      re the Prince of Wales' Visit to Yugoslavia
    - Speech of Prince of Wales at Dinner in Belgrade 1978 Oct (Box 6)
    - Memorabilia of the Prince of Wales' Visit to Yugoslavia and News clippings 1978 Oct (Box 6)
    - Memo and Notes on Tito 1978 Oct (Box 6)
    - Correspondence 1978 (Box 6)
      re Fitzroy Maclean's article for the British-Yugoslav Society on the Prince of Wales' visit
    - Memo 1980 May (Box 6)
      re Arrangements for the British Delegation to Tito's Funeral
    - Eulogy for Tito by Stevan Doraonjski, Chairman of the Presidency of the Central Committee of the League of Communists 1980 May (Box 6)
    - Remarks of Fitzroy Maclean in Korcula at the Wedding of Jamie Maclean 1983 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence including Elizabeth Barker and Dragi Stamenkovic, Yugoslav Ambassador 1984-1985 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence and Memos 1988-1989 (Box 6)
      re Official Visit of Fitzroy Maclean
    - Mitko Calovski and Budimir Loncar to Fitzroy Maclean 1989 May (Box 6)
    - Notes for Maclean's Interview with Ante Markovic 1989 (Box 6)
    - Transcript in Serbo-Croatian of Maclean's Interview with Prime Minister Ante Markovic 1989 Oct 30 (Box 6)
    - Statement by Ante Markovic 1989 Dec (Box 6)
      re Program of Economic Reform
    - Correspondence with Mark Thompson of Mladina, a Slovene weekly 1989-1991 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence with Jasper Ridley 1990-1991 (Box 6)
      re his biography of Tito
    - Correspondence 1990-1992 (Box 6)
      re Controversy over British Military Mission in World War II
    - Correspondence 1991-1992 (Box 6)
      re BBC "Timewatch: Tito" Program
    - Correspondence with and Articles by Stevan Dedijer 1991-1992 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence with A.W. Brian Simpson 1991-1992 (Box 6)
      re a Yugoslav Detainee in 1945
    - Correspondence 1991 Sep- 1992 May, 2 folders (Box 6)
      re Korcula, Croatia Emergency Appeal
    - Articles about Korcula, Croatia Emergency Mission 1991-1992 (Box 7)
    - Articles about Korcula, Croatia Emergency Mission by Veronica Maclean 1991-1992 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence 1992 Jan-Feb (Box 7)
      re Benefit Concert for Dubrovnik
    - Correspondence with David Owen and Fitzroy Maclean's Letter to The Times1992 Sep-Oct (Box 7)
      re Owen's Mission
    - Correspondence 1994 (Box 7)
      re Aldington-Tolstoy Libel Case (Repatriations in 1945)
    - Correspondence 1965-1977, 3 folders (Box 7)
      re Tito Memoirs and other projects
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1964-1973, 6 folders (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence 1975-1996, 12 folders (Box 8)
    - Research Material for an article on Korcula's History by Ambroz Kapor n.d. (Box 8)
  - Family & Personal Papers
    - Fitzroy and Veronica Maclean to Charles and Gladys Maclean 1939-1955, n.d., 8 folders (Box 9)
    - Charles and James Maclean to Charles Maclean; Charles Maclean to Fitzroy Maclean; and others 1953, 1957, 1965 (Box 9)
    - Family Financial Record 1946 (Box 8)
    - Wills of Charles and Gladys Maclean 1949, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Personal/ Family Correspondence 1963, 1993, n.d. (Box 9)
    - Personal Correspondence, including some documents re military service, in French, German, Italian, and English 1928-1952, 5 folders (Box 9)
    - Personal Correspondence: A.F.R. Wollaston of King's College, Cambridge 1929 Jan 25 (Box 9)
    - Personal Correspondence 1946 (Box 9)
      re Purchase of "Beechfield"
    - Personal Correspondence with Fitzgerald Bemiss 1980 (Box 9)
      re Ticonderoga story
    - Personal Correspondence 1995 (Box 9)
      re Purchase of "Creggans Inn"
    - Personal Correspondence with Frank McLynn 1990-1994 (Box 9)
      re Fitzroy Maclean
    - Personal Correspondence with Martin Stannard 1991-1992 (Box 9)
      re Evelyn Waugh biography
    - Book Reviews of Fitzroy Maclean by Frank McLynn 1992-1993 (Box 10)
    - Calling Cards ca. 1929-1939, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Financial Records 1929-1946, 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Italian Residence Permit 1932 (Box 10)
    - Memorabilia, including Russian Railway Schedule, German vocabulary notebook, list of stamps, post cards, travel information, and luggage tag of British delegation to NATO Parliamentarians Conference ca. 1914-1940's, n.d., 6 folders (Box 10)
    - Scrapbook of News clippings, etc. 1939-1950, bound volume filed with ledgers (Box 10)
    - Scrapbook of Newsclippings 1944-1946, bound volume filed with legders (Box 10)
      re Fitzroy Maclean and Articles by him
  - Honors & Decorations
    - Citation for Croix de Guerre 1942, 1957 (Box 10)
    - Warrent of Appointment to the Most Excellent Order of the British Empire 1944 Aug 31 (Oversize H.S. 16)
    - Correspondence 1951-1972 (Box 10)
      re Awarding of Baronetcy and Arms
    - Citation Accompanying Medal (not present) Awarded to Fitzroy Maclean to Wear at the Coronation of Elizabeth II 1953 (Box 10)
    - Master of Arts Degree, King's College, Cambridge 1968 Dec 14 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence and Memorabilia 1968-1969 (Box 10)
      re Honorary Degree from the University of Glasgow
    - Correspondence 1970-1971 (Box 10)
      re Honorary Degree from Acadia University
    - Correspondence, Memorabilia, & Photographs 1971 (Box 10)
      re Honorary Degree from Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia, to Fitzroy Maclean and Tito
    - Program 1971-1972 (Box 10)
      re Honorary Degree from Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia, to Fitzroy Maclean and Tito, signed by Josip Broz Tito and Madame Jovanka Broz
    - Program for the Commencement of the American College of Switzerland, where Maclean awarded Honorary Degree 1979 Jun 9 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence, Diploma, Photographs, and Memorabilia 1983-1984 (Box 10)
      re Honorary Degree from Dundee University
    - Correspondence 1980-1996 (Box 10)
      re Special Air Service
    - Correspondence 1980-1993, 4 folders (Box 11)
      re the 23rd Special Air Service Regiment
    - Robert Fellowes, on behalf of Queen Elizabeth II 1993 Nov 1 (Box 11)
      re Installation of Fitzroy Maclean in the Order of theThistle
    - Correspondence 1993-1994 (Box 11)
      re Installation of Fitzroy Maclean in the Order of the Thistle
    - Correspondence 1993-1994, 3 folders (Box 11)
      re Appointment of Fitzroy Maclean in the Order of the Thistle--Congratulations
    - New clippings 1993-1994 (Box 11)
      re Appointment of Fitzroy Maclean in the Order of the Thistle
    - Correspondence 1995-1996 (Box 11)
      Order of the Thistle Ceremony
    - Correspondence and Memorabilia 1995-1996 (Box 11)
      re Freedom of Argyll and Bute
    - Letters of Congratulations from Elizabeth, the Queen Mother, to Fitzroy Maclean for receiving the Freedom of Argyll and Bute 1996 Feb-Mar (Box 11)
- Series II
  - Eastern Approaches Material
    - Drafts ca. 1948, 5 folders (Box 12)
    - Setting Copy 1949, 6 folders (Box 12)
    - Setting Copy 1949, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Letter from Michael Adeane, Private Secretary to King George VI, to Fitzroy Maclean 1948 Dec 4 (Box 13)
      re omitting part of an interview with the King about Yugoslavia from his book
    - Letter from Winston Churchill to Fitzroy Maclean 1949 Jan (Box 13)
      with comments about what Maclean had written about himself in the book
    - Telegram with Congratulations from Winston Churchill 1949 (Box 13)
    - Letter from Michael Adeane, Private Secretary to King George VI, to Fitzroy Maclean 1949 (Box 13)
      thanking him for the copy of his book sent to the King
    - Miscellaneous Letters including a note from Ian Flemming 1950-1954 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence with Jonathan Cape and Others, including a letter by Ian Flemming to Cape 1945-1950 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence with Jonathan Cape 1949-1972, 6 folders (Box 13)
    - Correspondence with Jonathan Cape 1980-1991 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence with Jonathan Cape 1949-1950 (Box 13)
      re Publicity
    - Correspondence with Jonathan Cape 1950-1951 (Box 13)
      Translations
    - Correspondence 1949-1956 (Box 14)
      re American Edition
    - Correspondence with Canongate Publishing Limited 1988-1989 (Box 14)
    - Correspondence--Fan Mail 1970-1972 (Box 14)
    - Correspondence 1983-1989
      re German Edition
    - Correspondence 1980-1988 (Box 14)
      re Paperback Edition
    - Correspondence with Penguin 1989-1993, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Correspondence 1952-1964, 5 folders (Box 14)
      re Proposed Film, with a copy of the script for the film, April 1956
    - Correspondence 1982-1990 (Box 14)
      re Proposed TV Series
    - Correspondence and Treatments 1991-1993, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Correspondence--Thank you Letters from Friends 1949-1950, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Correspondence 1954-1970 (Box 15)
      re Yugoslav Edition
    - Correspondence 1977-1981 (Box 15)
    - Contract with Jonathan Cape 1948 Nov 26 (Box 15)
    - Research and Notes ca. 1948 (Box 15)
    - Reviews 1949-1957, 1991 (Box 15)
    - Reviews--Paperback Edition 1982 (Box 15)
    - Royalty Statements 1980-1995 (Box 15)
    - Serialization in The People1949 (Box 15)
  - Yugoslavia Material
    - Disputed Barricade--Drafts Part I 1950-1956, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Disputed Barricade--Drafts Part II ca. 1950-1956, 5 folders (Box 16)
    - Disputed Barricade--Drafts Part II ca. 1950-1956, 7 folders (Box 16)
    - Disputed Barricade--Drafts Part II ca. 1950-1956, 1 folder (Box 17)
    - Disputed Barricade--Drafts Part III ca. 1950-1956, 6 folders (Box 17)
    - Disputed Barricade--Drafts Appendix and Notes ca. 1950-1956 (Box 17)
    - Disputed Barricade--Setting Copy Parts I-II, Chapters 1-10 1957, 4 folders (Box 17)
    - Disputed Barricade--Setting Copy Parts III, Chapters 11-16 1957, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Disputed Barricade--Correspondence with Jonathan Cape, Blanche Knopf 1955-1958, 1969 (Box 18)
    - Disputed Barricade--Correspondence with Anthony Eden 1955-1956 (Box 18)
    - Disputed Barricade--Correspondence with Vlatko Velebit, Yugoslav Ambassador 1954-1957 (Box 18)
      Letter of thanks on behalf of Tito
    - Disputed Barricade--Correspondence 1957-1961, 1985-1987 (Box 18)
      re American Edition, The Heretic
    - Disputed Barricade--Correspondence with Friends and Fans 1957-1974 (Box 18)
    - Disputed Barricade--Correspondence 1958, 1973 (Box 18)
      re Translations
    - Disputed Barricade--Advertisements 1957 (Box 18)
    - Disputed Barricade--Notes ca. 1950-1956 (Box 18)
      re German Forces in Yugoslavia
    - Disputed Barricade--Reviews 1957-1958, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Disputed Barricade--Research Material 1940, 1946-1951, 3 folders (Box 18)
      including "The Fourth Enemy Offensive" and some in Serbo-Croatian
    - Yugoslavia--Typescript and Correspondence 1965-1971 (Box 18)
    - The Battle of Neretva--Drafts 1969, 5 folders (Box 19)
    - The Battle of Neretva--Correspondence 1968-72, 1978-79, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - The Battle of Neretva--Maps and Lists of Captions 1970 (Box 19)
    - Tito: A Pictorial Biography--Drafts in Notebooks ca. 1980, 4 folders (Box 19)
    - Tito: A Pictorial Biography--Drafts, Chapters 1-18 1980, 5 folders (Box 20)
    - Tito: A Pictorial Biography--Galleys 1980 (Box 20)
    - Tito: A Pictorial Biography--Correspondence with McGraw Hill and Others 1979-1983 (Box 20)
    - Tito: A Pictorial Biography--Correspondence with Macmillan and Others 1980-1982 (Box 20)
    - Tito: A Pictorial Biography--Correspondence 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 20)
      re Book Promotion Tour in Yugoslavia
    - Tito: A Pictorial Biography--Yugoslav Newspaper articles 1981 (Box 20)
    - Tito: A Pictorial Biography--Research Material 1974-1979, 4 folders (Box 21)
      including some correspondence and notes
    - Tito: A Pictorial Biography--Reviews 1980-1982 (Box 21)
    - Articles 1946-1993, 9 folders (Box 21)
    - Articles--"An Adriatic Idyll" 1989 Sep (Box 22)
      re Korcula by Charles Maclean
    - Articles--"Korcula" by Veronica Maclean n.d. (Box 22)
    - Articles--"Land of the Black Mountain" 1966 (Box 22)
    - Articles--"Marshall Plan for the Balkans?" 1995 (Box 22)
    - Articles--Tito 1964-1965, 1971 (Box 22)
    - Articles--"Tito Talks to Fitzroy Maclean" 1969 (Box 22)
    - Articles--Tito article in The Washington Post1976 (Box 22)
    - Articles--Tito obituary, with correspondence about it with The Daily Mail and The Sunday Times1976-1977 (Box 22)
    - Articles--Tito obituary in The Daily Telegraph, with correspondence re terms 1977-1980 (Box 22)
    - Articles for The Times, with correspondence 1980 (Box 22)
    - Articles--"Travel to Korcula" 1993 (Box 22)
    - Articles & Notes--"Whither Yugoslavia" 1989-1990, 2 folders (Box 22)
      Unpublished
    - Articles--Text of Yugoslavia with notes [1990] (Box 22)
    - Book Reviews 1946-1953 (Box 22)
    - Book Reviews-- The Adriatic Islands and Corfu by Celia Irving 1971 (Box 22)
    - Book Reviews-- Approach March by Julian Amery 1973 (Box 22)
    - Book Reviews-- The Embattled Mountain by F.W.D. Deakin 1971 (Box 22)
    - Book Review-- Europe's Backyard War by Mark Almond and Bosnia: A Short History by Noel Malcolm 1994 (Box 22)
    - Book Reviews-- The Fall of Yugoslavia by Misha Glenny 1992 (Box 22)
    - Book Reviews-- Tito: A Biography by Phyllis Auty 1970 (Box 22)
    - Book Reviews-- Yugoslavia and the Soviet Union by Stephan Clissold, The Yugoslav Experiment by Dennison Rusinow, When Men and Mountains Meet: the Explorers of the Western Himalayas, 1820-75 by John Keay, and The Mountain of Serbia by Anne Kindersley 1977 (Box 22)
    - Book Reviews-- Tito and the Rise and Fall of Yugoslavia by Richard Wesr and Tito by Jasper Ridley 1994 (Box 22)
    - Introduction to the Reissue of William Deakin's The Embattled Mountain, including correspondence with Oxford University Press 1993-1994 (Box 22)
    - Lectures on Tito 1968-1982 (Box 23)
    - Lecture "The Soviet-Yugoslav Dispute" at the Royal Institute of International Affairs 1949 Dec 6 (Box 23)
    - Lecture on Yugoslavia 1952 Feb 27 (Box 23)
    - Lecture "Yugoslavia" at NATO Defense College 1962 May 14 (Box 23)
    - Lecture/Speech at a [World War II Veteran's Event?] 1992 Mar (Box 23)
    - Lecture at Hay-on-Wye 1995 (Box 23)
    - Notes on Tito in Serbo-Croatian, French, German, and Italian n.d. (Box 23)
    - Preface for Tito: A Biography by Phyllis Auty 1970 (Box 23)
    - Radio--Correspondence 1967-1968 (Box 23)
      re of BBC Radio Broadcast on Mission to Tito
    - Radio--Correspondence 1964-1965 (Box 23)
      re Tito obituary for BBC Radio
    - Radio--Correspondence 1969 (Box 23)
      re BBC Radio "I Was There"
    - Radio--Transcript of BBC Radio Transcripts 1946-1962, 3 folders (Box 22)
    - Radio--Transcripts of BBC Radio Broadcast "Portrait of Marshal Tito" 1964 (Box 23)
    - Radio--Transcripts from Radio 4 Program on Tito 1969 Mar 12 (Box 23)